<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xwikidoc>
<web>DungeonMaster</web>
<name>CardolanEmpire</name>
<language></language>
<defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
<translation>0</translation>
<parent>Erithnoi History</parent>
<creator>XWiki.TodHarter</creator>
<author>XWiki.TodHarter</author>
<customClass></customClass>
<contentAuthor>XWiki.TodHarter</contentAuthor>
<creationDate>1335684905000</creationDate>
<date>1337577721000</date>
<contentUpdateDate>1337577721000</contentUpdateDate>
<version>2.1</version>
<title>The Cardolan Empire</title>
<template></template>
<defaultTemplate></defaultTemplate>
<validationScript></validationScript>
<comment></comment>
<minorEdit>false</minorEdit>
<syntaxId>xwiki/2.1</syntaxId>
<hidden>false</hidden>
<content>About 2 centuries after the destruction of Ugar, almost exactly 1000 years ago, a great ship made landfall on the eastern shore of Othan. This was the tall ship of Erithnoi the Great, and a fleet said to number 1000 ships followed him. These were the Cardolans, refugees fleeing the destruction of their original homeland. They came from a continent far across the Untread Waters to find a rich and sparsely populated land. They promptly founded the city of Cardol and began to build an empire. Cardolan chronology begins on year one of the founding of Cardol.

Over the next few centuries Cardol became the capital city of the mighty Cardolan Empire, which grew to encompass all but the most northerly areas of Erithnoi. The Tanaran peoples were unable to hold their own against the more advanced Cardolan society and were either slowly pushed back or incorporated into the Cardolan state, which grew as its population increased. Within four centuries the Empire reached its fullest extent, although the population continued to grow almost until the great collapse.

During this time much land was cleared of forest cover, roads and bridges built, cities founded and wars fought. The Tanarans and the western nomads were subdued. Evil humanoids and giants who had inhabited some lands were killed or driven out. Several orders of magi were founded at this time, great temples were built and much of Erithnoi was civilized. As the resources of the new land were exploited trade grew and new cities multiplied and expanded.

== Collapse ==


The strength of the Cardolan Empire was also its weakness. The armies of Cardol were hard pressed to protect the Empire which they had created. The Cardolan population was small compared with the size of the land which it controlled and enemies, attracted by the riches of its civilization always lurked on the borders and in the wilderness areas which still extended over many regions. The various descendants of the House of Erithnoi fought over the succession to his throne. Armies badly needed for defense were squandered in internal conflicts during the 6^^th^^ and early 7^^th^^ centuries. Most ill of all the Empire began to be beset by external enemies, barbarians to the north, nomads to the west, evil humanoids in the hinterlands and wilds, and evil things everywhere.

In 597, with the help of an elven contingent, a great force of evil humanoids was destroyed in the Battle of Telikorn Moor. This temporarily removed the threat of invasion. However in 625 the War of the Three Emperors broke out between rival claimants to the Emerald Throne. During its height in 629 the White Order, the order of magi which was charged with protecting Imperial order, removed the Orb, Scepter, and Crown of Erithnoi. These had been brought with him by Erithnoi from over the sea and were the symbols of imperial authority. During the struggles following this act the great tower of Tan-Kar-Nak, their stronghold, was razed to the ground and the Imperial Regalia disappeared forever.

In 637 another and greater humanoid incursion put an end to the fighting. The two remaining factions made uneasy truce, but were unable to resist the invasion. The Empire had been greatly weakened by this internal strife. Furthermore the Eldarin Lords of the Elfan Holds, who had up to this time contributed to the defense of the Empire withdrew their support, so diminished had the prestige of the Emerald Throne become. The powerful magi of the White Order were gone and there was much suspicion on all sides. Still the Cardolans mustered a great army containing all their finest troops and most potent weapons. The resulting Battle of 5 Mile Bridge was an unmitigated disaster for the Imperial armies. The entire Cardolan force was wiped out. In 638 the City of Cardol itself was sacked, burned, and razed to the ground.

Although in 652 the humanoids were dispersed at the Battle of the Seareach Hills by Meltitharn I Orc Slayer the social and economic fabric of the Empire had been destroyed and could not be restored. The Emerald Throne was no more, and no Emperor held the Orb, Scepter, and Rod. Perhaps worse still the White Order no longer existed. The arcane arm of Imperial might had been broken. Still the Empire did not die overnight. Several more Emperors ruled until finally Emperor Erithnoi VI, last of the House of Erithnoi perished and the destruction of imperial power of the last 50 years was complete.

Thus began the dark centuries of an epoch of adventure which continues to this day. In the east the barbarian Othani came to power under their great chieftain Aar Orno. This was the populous heart of the old Empire and its last remnants were absorbed into the new Kingdom of Othan, which remained intact and has grown slowly in power over the last 3 centuries.

The more northerly regions of Sildune, Kinergh, and Vye Elek were devastated by humanoids and only a few towns survived. To the west of Othan the Midrealms, lying between Othan and the Elfan Holds were also badly decimated. Later campaigns by the Othani kings and some of the elves dispersed the more powerful humanoid tribes, but much of the population of this area was destroyed along with the majority of the towns. Monsters and evil forces took root in the pillaged land. Only in the last 100 years have humans begun to slowly reclaim this area and it is now made up of a patchwork of different enclaves of all sorts. Warfare is constant and only the strongest survive for long.

In the west nomads occupied the area south of the Sea of Amak. Eventually they became somewhat more civilized, founded the City of Khemkal and the Oronate of Khem arose. Khem now occupies the lands west of the Holburgs and south of the Sea of Amak as far south as the town of Eldon on the Gilduni frontier.

Between Khem and the Beldethian River the destruction was less complete. With the support of the elves and dwarves the remaining human population was able to establish the Kingdom of Gilduin, which is one of the strongest of the successor states to the Empire. Gilduin controls all the territory as far north as Kinergh and from the Beldethian in the east to the borders of Khem in the northwest. To the south it extends around Khem Bay as far as the Iselbod River.</content></xwikidoc>
