<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xwikidoc>
<web>DungeonMaster</web>
<name>CivarianTomb</name>
<language></language>
<defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
<translation>0</translation>
<parent>DungeonMaster.ForestOfGrin</parent>
<creator>XWiki.TodHarter</creator>
<author>XWiki.TodHarter</author>
<customClass></customClass>
<contentAuthor>XWiki.TodHarter</contentAuthor>
<creationDate>1337567541000</creationDate>
<date>1337567634000</date>
<contentUpdateDate>1337567634000</contentUpdateDate>
<version>4.1</version>
<title>Tomb of the Civarian Kings</title>
<template></template>
<defaultTemplate></defaultTemplate>
<validationScript></validationScript>
<comment></comment>
<minorEdit>false</minorEdit>
<syntaxId>xwiki/2.1</syntaxId>
<hidden>false</hidden>
<content>Deep in the [[Forest Of Grin&gt;&gt;ForestOfGrin]] lies the tomb of the last of the kings of Civari. The following encounter areas exist.

== Swift Flow Crossing ==

The ancient road leading to the area of the tomb once crossed this stream by a stone bridge. The stream itself runs in a gorge about 30 feet deep, its waters boiling and foaming over great boulders and ledges of rock. The road appears to continue on the other side of the stream. Only the eastern (far) half of the bridge still stands. A 20' wide section on the western end has long since fallen into the water below.

Several methods of crossing are possible. A tree growing at the western side of the bridge could be cut and allowed to fall across the gap. Or a character may notice that a large tree on the other side has a sturdy limb which hangs out over the gap which could be taken advantage of. A third possibility would be climbing down into the gorge, crossing on chunks of rock, and climbing back up.

Each of these is a level 8 skill challenge of complexity 1. Success using any of the options allows the party to cross without incident (though they may loose some surges).

=== Cutting the Tree ===

Cutting the tree will require a DC14 Perception check to see where the tree should be cut and a DC14 Nature check to make the proper cut. A DC14 Athletics check will help guide the tree into place. A DC14 History check will give +2 (one time) on one of these rolls. At least one success must come from Nature, Athletics, and Perception each. Failure in the challenge means the tree falls into the ravine and the noise of its fall alerts the dryads in the next encounter area.

=== Swinging Across ===

The overhanging limb can be used in various ways to get across. A rope could be hooked to it via a grapple, etc. A DC14 Nature check is required to recognize which limb is ideal. Use of a grapple will require a DC14 Perception check in order to determine if the hook has bitten. Failure means the rope comes loose. Success means it is safely anchored. A DC14 Acrobatics check can be used to swing across. A DC14 Athletics check can be used to climb the rope to the branch and then down the tree. Once a character gets across with a rope the rest of the party can cross by making DC14 Endurance, Athletics, or Acrobatics checks. Each failure in this challenge costs the failing character a healing surge due to falling, bruising etc. Failure of the entire challenge means the last character to make a check falls into the ravine, suffering a loss of 2 healing surges.

=== Climbing Down and Back Up ===

This is the most basic way to cross. DC14 Athletics checks allow the PCs to climb down and back up again. DC14 Perception checks allow them to find the best way forward. DC14 Nature checks allow them to avoid loose rock or slippery spots. DC14 Endurance checks allow them to endure wading through the cold water. DC14 Acrobatics checks allow them to hop across on rocks. No more than 2 checks can be attempted with each of the above skills. Each failure costs the failing character 1 healing surge. Failure costs the last character to make a check to loose 2 healing surges as he takes a bad fall or is swept downstream and nearly drowned.

== The Other Side ==

On the east side of the bridge the ground rises a bit, cutting off the view of what is ahead. The ancient path climbs for about 40 feet and then veers to the north where it opens into a clear area about 60' across. This area is ringed with small stones and 4 larger menhirs. Within the circle are 3 large trees spaced about 40' apart.

The following creatures are present:



|=Creature|=Level|=XP|=Book
|Shambling Mound|9|400|MM
|Dryad|9|400|MM
|Vine Horror|5|200|MM
|Vine Horror Spellfiend|7|300|MM
|Hamadryad|11|150|DRAC
|Hamadryad|11|150|DRAC
|Total XP||%CALC{"$SUM( $ABOVE() )"}%|The party can achieve surprise against the enemy if they can each achieve a stealth check roll of TBD.

As soon as the creatures become aware of the party they will attack.

== Tomb Entrance ==

At the northwest corner of the clearing a rushing waterfall can be seen plunging down the sheer face of the hill to the north and into the ravine to the west. At this point there is a space where the clearing approaches the edge of the ravine. Upon inspection it will be seen that a steep stone stair carved into the side of the ravine leads down to the level of a pool at the base of the falls. A path appears to lead around to the edge of the falls themselves.

Behind the falls is the entrance to the tomb itself. The entrance has been worn partially away by time and the flow of water but a DC14 Dungeoneering check will reveal that it is not natural.

== The Upper Vaults ==

Once the entrance has been passed the tomb quickly opens out into a chamber. Three

== The Lower Vault ==</content></xwikidoc>
