<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xwikidoc>
<web>DungeonMaster</web>
<name>ClosingTheShadowgate</name>
<language></language>
<defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
<translation>0</translation>
<parent>DungeonMaster.MidrealmsCampaign5</parent>
<creator>XWiki.TodHarter</creator>
<author>XWiki.TodHarter</author>
<customClass></customClass>
<contentAuthor>XWiki.TodHarter</contentAuthor>
<creationDate>1337568778000</creationDate>
<date>1337568843000</date>
<contentUpdateDate>1337568843000</contentUpdateDate>
<version>2.1</version>
<title>ClosingTheShadowgate</title>
<template></template>
<defaultTemplate></defaultTemplate>
<validationScript></validationScript>
<comment></comment>
<minorEdit>false</minorEdit>
<syntaxId>xwiki/2.1</syntaxId>
<hidden>false</hidden>
<content>== Capture ==

When the party leaves the Moss Grotto Mali will appear with a numerous group of RangersOfHighUrieth who will release WarlockValanar, who is a captain of the rangers. Valanar will accuse the party of accosting him and hint that they may be treacherously attempting to thwart closing the shadowgate of the Vuul. He will agree to have the PCs returned to the Otillis Lodge in Smick's Knob while he and a few of the rangers state that they will go to the gate and perform the closing ritual.

In case the PCs wish to fight, the following figures will be present at the 'arrest'. ElfMali (Level 4 elf ranger/warlock), 6 Elf Noble Guards, 4 Ninaran Elf Archers, and Valanar (sans 1/4 of his hit points and presumably disarmed). The archers will remain concealed until and unless a fight develops while Mali and the guards engage the party.

== Captivity ==

The party will be marched back to the Otillis Lodge. When the party arrives at the lodge Valanar will have a confrontation with the elvish elder Ereglion and Father Barmin. Valanar will assert his authority to deal with the gate, send Jargosh and his 4 knights down to the village to 'keep the humans in order', and then have the party locked up in 2 of the upstairs rooms of the lodge. At this point, Celia will begin acting strangely, saying things like "he's calling me, I must go to him." This will drive Father Barmin and Ardur into fits. At this point Valanar will detail Mali and 6 guards to remain at the lodge to keep order, take Celia, saying "I will need her", and the rest of his rangers off to the gate. He will leave no doubt that he will "deal with you humans later, when it is convenient."

A bit later Father Barmin will have Ardur bring each group of PCs a dinner tray, under which he will slip them a note from Barmin. "I fear this Valanar character will do something terrible to my sweet Cecily. He is up to no good." Ardur will also smuggle 2 daggers in with him, one to each room, which the PCs are clearly intended to use to mount an escape. </content></xwikidoc>
