<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xwikidoc>
<web>DungeonMaster</web>
<name>CouncilOfTwelve</name>
<language></language>
<defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
<translation>0</translation>
<parent>DungeonMaster.LadyNellaKellion</parent>
<creator>XWiki.TodHarter</creator>
<author>XWiki.TodHarter</author>
<customClass></customClass>
<contentAuthor>XWiki.TodHarter</contentAuthor>
<creationDate>1337569304000</creationDate>
<date>1337569340000</date>
<contentUpdateDate>1337569340000</contentUpdateDate>
<version>1.1</version>
<title>CouncilOfTwelve</title>
<template></template>
<defaultTemplate></defaultTemplate>
<validationScript></validationScript>
<comment></comment>
<minorEdit>false</minorEdit>
<syntaxId>xwiki/2.1</syntaxId>
<hidden>false</hidden>
<content>The Council of Twelve is an executive council which was formed in the year 1001 during the invasion of the [[GreenAdept&gt;&gt;url:http://www.giantelectronicbrain.com/twiki/bin/view/DungeonMaster/GreenAdept||class="twikiLink"]]. It initially consisted of the lords of the 7 lordships of Kinergh most directly impacted by the invasion, plus a representative from Highhold, and one from Dalcaroth. In addition 3 of the Council members represented major temple cults, Klay, Atur, and Otillis. As the crisis deepened additional participants were added representing the southern lordships and several other factions, including the priesthoods of Lir, Yilliki, and Teala. Although this means the Council now has more than the original 12 members the name has stuck. Formally it is however now known as the Grand Council of the Northern League. A more restricted subset, sometimes confusingly also called the Council of Twelve includes only the lords of Kinergh itself plus the high priest of the Temple of Klay (Lach Klay) who acts as Chairman. This later subgroup is effectively the privy council of a reconstituted Kingdom of Kinergh, though unless and until Sharn Kellion II can pass the (% class="twikiNewLink" %)TestOfAtur[[?&gt;&gt;url:http://www.giantelectronicbrain.com/twiki/bin/edit/DungeonMaster/TestOfAtur?topicparent=DungeonMaster.CouncilOfTwelve||rel="nofollow" title="Create this topic"]](%%) and assume the crown it lacks an official capacity.

One of the main difficulties faced by the Council is a lack of any direct executive mechanism. Participation is at least nominally voluntary and the Council lacks its own government departments. It instead must rely on the officers of the various lordships to carry out its directives. The Duke of Tisloch has a well-developed organs of government in the form of the RoseCourtOfTiliniel. These however don't have authority in the other lordships. Some of these officers and departments however have served to implement the Council's policies. For instance the Marshal of Tisloch serves as the commander of the combined army of Kinergh. Most other policies have simply been implemented piece-wise by the various lords and their officials, such as levies of men and materials, monetary contributions, intelligence gathering, etc.

The Council is rarely entirely united in advocating a single policy. Each of the lords has varying agendas and some, such as those aligned with the ForlarrenFaction actively oppose any tendency of the Council to assume responsibility for nationwide policies. As a result the Council has only limited effectiveness. It has however served in a crisis to allow at least a modicum of coordination of effort between the lords. However with the defeat of the invading forces the Council has had difficulty coming to any significant agreement on further actions and has not met since the fall of 1003.

A Council meeting is scheduled to be held at Talimath Castle during the festival of Council 1004. Exactly what may be accomplished during this meeting will depend on events leading up to it. Some of the lords are likely to advocate the dissolution of the Council entirely, but many (most of the northern lords) are intent on continuing cooperation, fearing the possibility of further invasions. They are also eager to access some of the resources of the south, which was largely untouched by the invasion and has greater available resources. Most of the southern lords are still participating mostly because they see an opportunity to gain rights to resources available in the north as a price for continued cooperation.</content></xwikidoc>
