<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xwikidoc>
<web>DungeonMaster</web>
<name>DragonAmaranth</name>
<language></language>
<defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
<translation>0</translation>
<parent>DungeonMaster.NPCs</parent>
<creator>XWiki.TodHarter</creator>
<author>XWiki.TodHarter</author>
<customClass></customClass>
<contentAuthor>XWiki.TodHarter</contentAuthor>
<creationDate>1336368210000</creationDate>
<date>1336368383000</date>
<contentUpdateDate>1336368383000</contentUpdateDate>
<version>2.1</version>
<title>Dragon Amaranth</title>
<template></template>
<defaultTemplate></defaultTemplate>
<validationScript></validationScript>
<comment></comment>
<minorEdit>false</minorEdit>
<syntaxId>xwiki/2.1</syntaxId>
<hidden>false</hidden>
<content>Amaranth is a silver elder wyrm which makes its lair in the high peak above the dwarven city of Dalcaroth. While the dragon has defended the city in the past it has grown sleepy of late and has not stirred visibly from its lair in 50 years. Now evil dragons of the north have begun to encroach further south than of old. It is rumored that Amaranth is still active through agents, but there are also rumors that the dragon is dead or otherwise incapacitated.

== Lore ==

Streetwise: DC30 Amaranth is known to have entrusted several dwarves of incorruptible integrity to maintain its contacts. It is not known if they receive instructions from the dragon or if they are simply operating based on their own resources and knowledge of the dragon's wishes.

Streetwise: DC35 There is at least one dwarven adventurer who has been known to let it slip that Amaranth itself gives advice to certain highly trusted adventurers. Strangely it is difficult to get anyone to confirm this tale, but that may be accomplished with the use of other skills.

Streetwise: DC40 Amaranth still lives, but he expended a great deal of energy in a fight with an ancient white worm, Xagras, 65 years ago. Since then he has retired from active defense and remains within his lair. At times he will awaken and is said to have given some trusted persons telepathic access to him. He rarely sees anyone directly and prefers that his condition is not known. He is still capable of fighting, but believes his next fight will be his last.

= History =

Amaranth is one of, and possibly the, oldest living mortal creature in Erithnoi. He is almost 10 thousand years old. Born near the end of the war between the Younger and Elder Gods which destroyed the First World he was amongst the first to make the journey to Erth. He can remember the day when Olorin opened the ways and mortal races first came to the untamed world and the gods walked amongst them for the last time. Soon he will be gone and with him all living memory of those times.

Later Amaranth participated in the (% class="twikiNewLink" %)DragonWars(%%) and finally joined with the ancient dwarves of the north in their war against the giants who had enslaved them. At one time he made his lair at the base of the great central shaft of Alcon and advised the kings of Civari. When Civari fell he was instrumental in reestablishing the northern dwarves in Dalcaroth where he now lairs.

When the Cardolans first came to the west of Erithnoi Amaranth, already vastly ancient, gave them much of his knowledge. The mages of the (% class="twikiNewLink" %)White Order(%%) in particular learned many secrets and Amaranth hoped that the empire they upheld would finally bring a great age of peace and learning. All too soon the empire crumbled and Amaranth retreated to his lair. Since those days he has spent his waning strength only to help secure and defend his ancient dwarven allies in Dalcaroth and now barely stirs at all.</content></xwikidoc>
