<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xwikidoc>
<web>DungeonMaster</web>
<name>DragonTuratha</name>
<language></language>
<defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
<translation>0</translation>
<parent>DungeonMaster.NPCs</parent>
<creator>XWiki.TodHarter</creator>
<author>XWiki.TodHarter</author>
<customClass></customClass>
<contentAuthor>XWiki.TodHarter</contentAuthor>
<creationDate>1336368408000</creationDate>
<date>1336368451000</date>
<contentUpdateDate>1336368451000</contentUpdateDate>
<version>1.1</version>
<title>Dragon Turatha</title>
<template></template>
<defaultTemplate></defaultTemplate>
<validationScript></validationScript>
<comment></comment>
<minorEdit>false</minorEdit>
<syntaxId>xwiki/2.1</syntaxId>
<hidden>false</hidden>
<content>Turatha is an adult green dragon which lairs in the northeastern part of the [[ForestOfGrin&gt;&gt;url:http://www.giantelectronicbrain.com/twiki/bin/view/DungeonMaster/ForestOfGrin||class="twikiLink"]]. It hunts the forest and the south slopes of the mountains to the north, as well as ranging to the east as far as the Beldethian River and between the river and the Melthian Mountains.

Currently Turatha is mainly concerned with the appearance of the [[BlackDragonRaxitar&gt;&gt;url:http://www.giantelectronicbrain.com/twiki/bin/view/DungeonMaster/BlackDragonRaxitar||class="twikiLink"]] who has established a lair in the Relch Bog. Turatha would like to get rid of Raxitar, but is unable to confront the wiley black, which can retreat into the [[Shadowfell&gt;&gt;url:http://www.giantelectronicbrain.com/twiki/bin/view/DungeonMaster/FirstWorld||class="twikiLink"]] with ease. So far Raxitar has avoided confrontations with Turatha but it is certain that eventually the two almost equally matched dragons will have it out.

Needless to say Turatha would be greatly pleased with anyone who was able to dispose of Raxitar and if contacted he will certainly suggest this possibility. Turatha is not directly in the service of the [[GreenAdept&gt;&gt;url:http://www.giantelectronicbrain.com/twiki/bin/view/DungeonMaster/GreenAdept||class="twikiLink"]] but fears the later's power. He will not cooperate in any scheme which might bring him into conflict with the evil forces and will probably eventually be tempted to help them. So far the [[GreenAdept&gt;&gt;url:http://www.giantelectronicbrain.com/twiki/bin/view/DungeonMaster/GreenAdept||class="twikiLink"]] has never tried to enlist the dragon, probably because he knows that Turatha would be a fickle ally at best.</content></xwikidoc>
