<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xwikidoc>
<web>DungeonMaster</web>
<name>Kellhold</name>
<language></language>
<defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
<translation>0</translation>
<parent>DungeonMaster.OldStreet</parent>
<creator>XWiki.TodHarter</creator>
<author>XWiki.TodHarter</author>
<customClass></customClass>
<contentAuthor>XWiki.TodHarter</contentAuthor>
<creationDate>1336814804000</creationDate>
<date>1336816568000</date>
<contentUpdateDate>1336816568000</contentUpdateDate>
<version>3.1</version>
<title>Kellhold</title>
<template></template>
<defaultTemplate></defaultTemplate>
<validationScript></validationScript>
<comment></comment>
<minorEdit>false</minorEdit>
<syntaxId>xwiki/2.1</syntaxId>
<hidden>false</hidden>
<content>Kelhold is a town in far eastern [[Erklond&gt;&gt;doc:Erklond]], on the west bank of the Zel River, and thus on the border of Othan. Duke Harngrist of Malan has his seat here, maintaining a strong castle a few miles outside the town.

== Jerek Academy ==

This is the only significant magical teaching establishment in human-controlled areas of the Midrealms. Dwarves, elves, and other races have their own keepers of arcane lore, but only here can one learn magic for a fee and access a reasonably extensive magical library and related lore. Anyone wishing to do research or take classes must have recommendations and pay appropriate fees. 

The Academy is operated by the wizard Mariel Jerek. Her mother Alla Jerek founded the academy 40 years ago after fighting in the orc wars of Farlond. Mariel was a poor student and craved adventure more than study. She was lucky and smart enough to be successful as an adventurer for some time. Eventually she became famous for exploits of war magic, but after one fateful adventure in which her lover was lost in the Shadowfell she gave up adventuring and succeeded her mother as headmistress and proprietor of the academy.

There are 3 other lesser teachers who specialize in various aspects of magical training. Berb Halek, a grizzled but cheerful dwarf teaches alchemy and potion making. Orf Laden, a half-elf of indeterminate age who alternates between vague and dour teaches basics of ritual magic, specializing in divinations. The mysterious Kerek Akika teaches illusions, misdirections, charms, and other other such spells.

One may note that Kerek Akika appears human but is an unusual character, always wearing a fairly heavy black hooded robe. In fact he is a kenku, a bird man, who has learned to conceal his identity by illusion. He has some sort of relationship with Mariel Jerek or some kind of hold on her, a fact that might be discovered by observation over time (such as by a student). In fact Mariel is well aware that Kerek uses the knowledge he gains to help equip his flock with magic they can use in their various schemes. He teaches and she tolerates him, knowing that the wrath of the kenku flock would not be worth expelling Kerek. In fact he also often carries out commissions for the Duke of a sensitive nature. Kerek may not be well-liked, but his position is relatively secure.

Fees for attendance at the Academy are 1000gp per semester. This includes materials, room, and board. Use of the Academy library requires a fee of 50gp per day and access to the stacks is supervised. No books may be removed. The Academy may at times purchase lore books or accept them in trade for fees.</content></xwikidoc>
