<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xwikidoc>
<web>DungeonMaster</web>
<name>RoseCourtOfTiliniel</name>
<language></language>
<defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
<translation>0</translation>
<parent>DungeonMaster.Kinergh</parent>
<creator>XWiki.TodHarter</creator>
<author>XWiki.TodHarter</author>
<customClass></customClass>
<contentAuthor>XWiki.TodHarter</contentAuthor>
<creationDate>1337566146000</creationDate>
<date>1337569227000</date>
<contentUpdateDate>1337569227000</contentUpdateDate>
<version>6.1</version>
<title>RoseCourtOfTiliniel</title>
<template></template>
<defaultTemplate></defaultTemplate>
<validationScript></validationScript>
<comment></comment>
<minorEdit>false</minorEdit>
<syntaxId>xwiki/2.1</syntaxId>
<hidden>false</hidden>
<content>The Rose Court is the court of the Dukes of the Grand Duchy of Tisloch. The current Duke is His Excellence Duke Sharn Kellion II of Tisloch. The name Rose Court derives from the council hall at Castle Tiliniel where formal court is held. This hall was once the throne room of the King of Kinergh and Castle Tiliniel was the seat of the King. In fact Sharn Kellion himself has the most direct claim to the kingship of Kinergh and plans to reconstitute the kingdom itself if possible. By ancient tradition all members of the noble houses of Kinergh are entitled to attend court. Other persons with legitimate business must apply to the Chamberlain for permission to appear.

== Major Figures ==

There are numerous major and minor figures to be found at the court. The following are some of the more interesting.

* [[His Excellence Duke Sharn Kellion II&gt;&gt;SharnKellionII]] - Duke of Tisloch
* [[Sir Halden Marsh&gt;&gt;HaldenMarsh]] - The Marshal of Tisloch
* [[Lady Nella Kellion&gt;&gt;doc:LadyNellaKellion]] - The Duke's mother
* [[Baron Orlo of Weln]] - The Chamberlain of the Exchequer (treasurer).
* Telfasian - The court fool.
* Eberad Drellfus - The court magician.
* [[Baron Tredlo Hargraf&gt;&gt;BaronTredloHargraf]] - The Steward of the Rose Court.
* Baroness Wendelain Tredlow - Chancellor of Tisloch.
* Sir Mareth Carlin - Captain of the Royal Company (Duke's bodyguard).

== Other members of the Court ==

The Chancellor, Steward, Chamberlain, and Marshal all have several lesser officials, clerks, etc who assist them in the day-to-day execution of their tasks. The Steward is responsible for the normal staff of the court and the castle itself. The Chancellor is in charge of the various courts and civil policing functions, though many of these functions fall to lesser nobles. The Chamberlain manages the Duchy's finances and tax collection functions. The Marshal is the commander of the standing military forces. He has under his control various captains, etc.

Sharn Kellion's policy of consolidating the power of Tisloch over the other independent lordships of Kinergh makes him popular with his own court. On the other hand the local merchants are happy with the status quo, the other northern lords are needless to say mostly not in a position to seriously object. Accommodations have been made with the dwarves and only some of the southern lords are still powerful enough to make trouble.

Even so the [[Forlarren Faction&gt;&gt;ForlarrenFaction]] represents a group of nobles, influenced by the diabolic operatives of the [[Head Of Oboth Nai&gt;&gt;HeadOfObothNai]] who are dedicated to preventing a reinstatement of the Kingship of Kinergh. They are the spearhead in Kinergh of the Head's followers who are even now close to the brink of seizing power in Gilduin. Most of the Forlarren Faction are southern nobles, including [[Count Porthel Of ThangCountPorthelOfThang]], and [[Count Denthos Of Alas&gt;&gt;CountDenthosOfAlas]]. Baron Orlo Of Weln&gt;&gt;BaronOrloOfWeln]] , a retainer of the Duke himself is also one of the main, though covert, leaders of the faction.</content></xwikidoc>
