<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xwikidoc>
<web>DungeonMaster</web>
<name>StarSea</name>
<language></language>
<defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
<translation>0</translation>
<parent>DungeonMaster.Cosmology</parent>
<creator>XWiki.TodHarter</creator>
<author>XWiki.TodHarter</author>
<customClass></customClass>
<contentAuthor>XWiki.TodHarter</contentAuthor>
<creationDate>1587704730000</creationDate>
<date>1587705794000</date>
<contentUpdateDate>1587705794000</contentUpdateDate>
<version>1.1</version>
<title>The Star Sea</title>
<template></template>
<defaultTemplate></defaultTemplate>
<validationScript></validationScript>
<comment></comment>
<minorEdit>false</minorEdit>
<syntaxId>xwiki/2.1</syntaxId>
<hidden>false</hidden>
<content>This is an abstract non-corporeal realm of pure thought and ideas. Those who are able to ascend physically to the level of the celestial bodies will find that they have reached the end of the material realm, and all existence beyond this point becomes abstract. Travel, per se, in this realm is not really possible in a physical sense. One must use powerful spiritual techniques in order to travel as an astral entity in this realm. Within the Star Sea, or perhaps on its far shores, lie various other metaphysical realms which are the homes of higher beings. These higher beings themselves do not have fixed material forms, although some of them might manifest in the world as such.
Travel here can be quite dangerous, and because ordinary concepts like time and causality do not hold in the usual way it can be difficult for travellers to make their way or find a path to return by. Another danger is that while a traveller is in the astral state, his or her physical body remains behind at the location where the journey started. Powerful arcane practitioners will normally ward their bodies heavily, leave behind powerful guards, and/or entrust their safety to their most trustworthy associates in order to guarantee their survival. </content></xwikidoc>
