<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xwikidoc>
<web>DungeonMaster</web>
<name>TheArcanum</name>
<language></language>
<defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
<translation>0</translation>
<parent>DungeonMaster.Organizations</parent>
<creator>XWiki.TodHarter</creator>
<author>XWiki.TodHarter</author>
<customClass></customClass>
<contentAuthor>XWiki.TodHarter</contentAuthor>
<creationDate>1339372441000</creationDate>
<date>1339372593000</date>
<contentUpdateDate>1339372593000</contentUpdateDate>
<version>1.1</version>
<title>The Arcanum</title>
<template></template>
<defaultTemplate></defaultTemplate>
<validationScript></validationScript>
<comment></comment>
<minorEdit>false</minorEdit>
<syntaxId>xwiki/2.1</syntaxId>
<hidden>false</hidden>
<content>Known in Elvish as the Ha'ar Elium. In ancient times during the days of Civari a massive Arcane war erupted between the modern Eldar and their dark cousins the Drow. However this war was not as simple as good vs evil. Massive destruction was wrought, the cities of Civari, the (% class="twikiNewLink" %)ShadowKingdoms[[?&gt;&gt;url:http://www.giantelectronicbrain.com/twiki/bin/edit/DungeonMaster/ShadowKingdoms?topicparent=DungeonMaster.TheArcanum||rel="nofollow" title="Create this topic"]](%%) , and The Fey were all destroyed and the world entered a dark age. Eventually civilization and progress returned to Erithnoi and to the Eldar cities of the Fey, but never again did the Eldar share their knowledge and all their colleges of magic was drawn together to form the Arcanum. All those who enter swear to bear no children or give up those they bear. They live within strictly cloistered holds and to agree to specific restrictions on their communication with the outside world.

The secular authorities are responsible for supplying the Arcanum, but there is reciprocal production of goods. In addition members of the Arcanum can be summoned to serve the state, provide magical advice, and even participate in the defense of the Eldar cities. Often those requisitioned for service are forbidden to return to the Arcanum but some exceptions can be made. Discipline is high within the Arcanum and it is not unknown for members to be expelled for infractions of the rules.

Otherwise the members of the Arcanum preserve, assemble, and interpret all types of knowledge, especially that of the Arcane. Outside the Arcanum do exist other organizations and individuals with great knowledge, but the Arcanum has by far the greatest understanding of Magic of any of the Demi-human races. Because some of this knowledge is so dangerous that it cannot be allowed to be used the Arcanum exists. Any group which demonstrates similarly dangerous knowledge is put under the authority of the Arcanum. Thus no other group grows more powerful than it.

In fact the Arcanum has great knowledge and is still doing important research, but its main function has become more and more as a vault for that which should not be known.



== {{id name="The_Keystone"/}}The Keystone ==

One of the three (% class="twikiNewLink" %)KeyStones(%%) to the WellOfStars is in the possession of the Arcanum. In order to give it up the Arcanum Collegiate Council would have to determine that this action is in the best interests of the Eldar. Beyond this other major (% class="twikiNewLink" %)FeyPowers(%%) such as the (% class="twikiNewLink" %)SummerCourt(%%) would have to be involved. Gaining this permission would be a difficult high level adventure.</content></xwikidoc>
