<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xwikidoc>
<web>DungeonMaster</web>
<name>WildWoodManor</name>
<language></language>
<defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
<translation>0</translation>
<parent>DungeonMaster.ProdigalJack</parent>
<creator>XWiki.TodHarter</creator>
<author>XWiki.TodHarter</author>
<customClass></customClass>
<contentAuthor>XWiki.TodHarter</contentAuthor>
<creationDate>1336282006000</creationDate>
<date>1336282293000</date>
<contentUpdateDate>1336282293000</contentUpdateDate>
<version>2.1</version>
<title>WildWoodManor</title>
<template></template>
<defaultTemplate></defaultTemplate>
<validationScript></validationScript>
<comment></comment>
<minorEdit>false</minorEdit>
<syntaxId>xwiki/2.1</syntaxId>
<hidden>false</hidden>
<content>Wildwood Manor is an estate located in the western part of the [[Duchy Of Har&gt;&gt;doc:Player.DuchyOfHar]] in Kinergh. It was constructed about 80 years ago (in the 920's) by a Half Elven adventurer named Thandar Handalf. It is roughly 20 miles north of the [[Town of Lad&gt;&gt;doc:TownOfLad]], just on the eastern side of the Larelda Brook in a fairly remote location at the very edge of civilization. A trail leads from the (% class="twikiNewLink" %)Village of Har(%%) north west to the manor. Midway along this path is a small Otillis Lodge. This path continues beyond the manor, crosses Larelda Brook, and climbs up the (% class="twikiNewLink" %)Cliffs of Larelda(%%) and ultimately strikes the (% class="twikiNewLink" %)Dwarf Road(%%) to the west several miles south east of the gates of Alcon.

== The manor house and grounds ==

The manor itself is a large stone and log structure which is capable of housing as many as 50 people. Hobgoblins and other humanoids passed through this area on their way from the mountain passes to the west to the (% class="twikiNewLink" %)Vale of Lad(%%) and during that time the inhabitants were killed or driven off. Because the hobgoblins used the manor as a base of operations the buildings were left largely intact although looted and now in some state of disrepair.

The main house is a 2 story stone structure. The lower floor has modest sized windows in front, and a few small windows in back. All of them are equipped with bars and heavy shutters equipped with arrow slits. The upper windows are somewhat larger but also barred and shuttered. Two wings constructed log construction run back from the back of the house, one on each side. Behind these wings was a large barn which is now destroyed. The area between the wings was once a yard and herb gardens but is now overgrown with tall grass. To the front of the structure is an open lawn which is also now overgrown with tall grass.

100' to the west is Larelda Brook. There are overgrown fields surrounding the house in most directions extending at least 1000 feet. These are all somewhat overgrown and it is possible to approach within 5 squares of the house with concealment.

== Fortifying the House (skill challenge) ==

The manor is designed to be defensible, but it is built primarily as a residence, not a fortification. Furthermore it has suffered some damage and lack of regular maintenance over the last 2-3 years. The party will have to determine what the best area of the building to defend is, then come up with a defensive strategy, and finally make repairs and improvements in order to enhance their defensive plan. Each phase is a segment of the skill challenge.

=== Finding the best area to defend (mental) ===

**Primary Skill**: Insight

This part of the challenge requires the characters to explore the building to decide which area is the best defensive position. The party may pick ANY defensive position they like and use whatever defense plan they wish. Varying levels of success or failure at this part of the challenge will simply provide them with more or less choices of good locations and allow them to identify better materials to use in the later parts of the challenge.

Other skills which may be useful besides insight include Nature, Perception, History, and Streetwise. Each of these skills may be used one time.

=== Developing a Strategy (social) ===

**Primary Skill**: Diplomacy

This part of the challenge requires the characters to put their heads together and find the best place to put traps, which doors and windows to reinforce, identify what areas the enemy is most likely to attack, and lay out any escape paths or other contingency plans effectively. The actual plans the party will come up with and use are up to them, but the DM can provide more advice and also arrange the hobgoblin attack to more closely conform to the party's ideas if the challenge is successful.

Other skills which may be useful besides diplomacy include History, Insight, and Nature. Each of these skills may be used one time.

=== Building Defenses (physical) ===

**Primary Skill**: Endurance, Thievery

Actually building the defenses will require the characters to perform a good bit of physical work, hauling lumber, setting up traps, digging, etc. The results of their work will vary in quality and quantity depending on the level of success of the challenge.

=== Results ===

**Victory:** The party will have a choice of three locations within the Manor and its grounds to defend. Their plans will be well laid and the hobgoblins will initially attack exactly as they predict. Traps and other preparations will be numerous and effective. The party will be allowed to set up to 5 traps and or build up to 5 fortified elements (reinforcing a door or window, building a trench or pit, erecting a barricade, etc) or some combination of fortifications and traps up to 5 in total number. Each trap will have a DC of 18 to disarm, attack at +10 vs Selected Defense for 2d8 damage and require a DC18 Perception check to find. In addition the party should be given a wider range of choices of traps or other similar features because they will have discovered supplies of oil or whatever other materials are best suited to their plan.

**Partial Success**: The party will have a choice of two locations within the Manor and its grounds to defend. Their plans will be less well laid and the hobgoblins will attack from a random direction. Traps and other preparations will be only adequate. The party will be allowed to set up to 3 traps or build up to three fortified elements or some combination of the two. Each trap will have a DC of 14 to disarm, attack at +8 vs Selected Defense for 2d6 damage and require a DC14 Perception check to find. The choices of traps and other features will be somewhat limited, but there will still be choices. Only one minor special item can be discovered on the grounds which may be helpful.

**Failure**: The attempt at setting up a defense of the manor is not very successful at all. The party will discover one area which they can defend. They will be able to construct 2 traps or features. Each trap will have a DC 10 to disarm, attack at +6 vs Selected Defense for 2d4 damage and require a DC12 Perception check to find. Traps and features may only be constructed out of the simplest everyday items (wood, stone, rope).

== Treasure ==

No doubt the party will search the manor. In a locked chest hidden in an upstairs room they will find:

A Circlet of Authority

Level 7 Bracers of Defense

3 gems worth 500gp each.</content></xwikidoc>
