<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xwikidoc>
<web>Player</web>
<name>CharacterBackgrounds</name>
<language></language>
<defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
<translation>0</translation>
<parent>Player.WebHome</parent>
<creator>XWiki.TodHarter</creator>
<author>XWiki.TodHarter</author>
<customClass></customClass>
<contentAuthor>XWiki.TodHarter</contentAuthor>
<creationDate>1335753013000</creationDate>
<date>1335753235000</date>
<contentUpdateDate>1335753235000</contentUpdateDate>
<version>2.1</version>
<title>Character Backgrounds</title>
<template></template>
<defaultTemplate></defaultTemplate>
<validationScript></validationScript>
<comment></comment>
<minorEdit>false</minorEdit>
<syntaxId>xwiki/2.1</syntaxId>
<hidden>false</hidden>
<content>These backgrounds are available for player characters to select. They work with the standard 4e background rules found in the PHB2. These are not at all exclusive and other backgrounds may be developed or the generic backgrounds may be used. Select as many or as few of these as you wish.

== {{id name="Regional"/}}Regional ==

This category describes which region of Erithnoi the character originates from. Not all characters are required to select this as one of their background elements, but if you do you may gain some benefits associated with that area.These are regional benefits as described in PHB2 and are in addition to any for geography, society, birth, etc.

=== {{id name="Kinergh"/}}Kinergh ===

Your character hails from the rugged valleys and slopes of this small but ancient land. Kinergh is steeped in ancient history and lore. Many ancient ruines and great mysteries are associated with this land. Today its rugged inhabitants live at the frontier of civilization. Your character might be a rugged Ranger of Otillis, a fell Avenger of Gelin, a stout fighter, or a town wizard. The inhabitants of Kinergh take great pride in their ancient history and also excel in wilderness settings.You can add History to your class skill list or gain a +2 to skill checks with the History skill. Alternatively you may have proficiency with the Elven language.

=== {{id name="Eldoran_Isles"/}}Eldoran Isles ===

Your character grew up on one of the Eldoran Isles. Inhabitants of the Eldoran Isles are bold navigators who sail their ships all across the Ta-Al-Erg and even into the outer seas. You may have proficiency with a foreign language (Mnarian, Sarnian, Khemish, other human language). You also gain a +4 to all swim checks or may add Athletics to their class proficiency list when creating your character.

=== {{id name="Holburgs"/}}Holburgs ===

Your character comes from the Holburg Hills. This area is a group of hills surrounding the great dwarven city of Dalcaroth. Its inhabitants are known for their stubborn fighting skills and defensive tactics. You may take fluency in the dwarven language as a bonus language, add Dungeoneering to your class skills list or gain +2 to all Dungeoneering checks.

=== {{id name="Elfan_Holds"/}}Elfan Holds ===

Your character is an inhabitant of the Elfan Holds. This is the homeland of most elves in Erithnoi and many eldar are also found here. You may take fluency in elvish or gain either a +2 to all Arcana skill checks or add arcana to your class skills list when creating your character.

=== {{id name="Erklond"/}}Erklond ===

Your character comes from the wild and uncivilized region of Erklond. This region is home to tribes of wandering humans who live by hunting and gathering. You may add +2 to all skill checks for either Nature or Endurance, or add one of these skills to your class skill list when creating your character.

=== {{id name="Midrealms"/}}Midrealms ===

Your character hails from the lawless and disorderly lands lying between Othan and the Elfan Holds. You may add +2 to either Intimidate or Insight skill checks or add either Intimidate or Insight to your class skill list.

=== {{id name="Principality_of_Ek"/}}Principality of Ek ===

Your character originates from the Principality of Ek. This area is dominated by a caste system in which arcane adepts form the ruling elite. You may add Arcana to your class skill list or take a +2 bonus to Arcana checks.

=== {{id name="Gilduin"/}}Gilduin ===

Your character comes from the Kingdom of Gilduin. Gilduin is one of the most civilized and powerful nations in Erithnoi. You may add diplomacy to your class skill list or take a +2 to all Diplomacy skill checks.

=== {{id name="Othan"/}}Othan ===

=== {{id name="Vye_Elek"/}}Vye-Elek ===

Your character hails from the County of Vye-Elek. This small hold borders on the lands of the hobgoblins to the north and its inhabitants are known for their hatred of all goblinoids. You may add Heal to your class skill list or take a +2 to all Heal skill checks.

=== {{id name="Seareach_City"/}}Seareach City ===

Your character hails from the great port of Seareach City at the mouth of the Beldethian River. You may add Streetwise to your class skill list when you create your character or take +2 on all Streetwise skill checks.

=== {{id name="Mnaria"/}}Mnaria ===

Your character hails from the ancient far southern land of Mnaria which lies to the south of the Ta-Al-Erg. The corrupt and ancient ways of the cities of Mnaria have prepared you well for a life of intrigue. You may take a +2 to skill checks with the Streetwise or Insight skills, or add one of these skills to your class skills list when you create your character. In addition you are fluent in the Mnarian language instead of Common.

=== {{id name="Sildune"/}}Sildune ===

=== {{id name="Kazan"/}}Kazan ===

Your character comes from the land of Kazan. Kazan is a realm in far northeast of Erithnoi. The inhabitants are a race of doughty humans who make much of their living from the sea and by raiding more southerly lands. Giants constantly threaten to overrun Kazan and its heroes are known to be fearless giant killers. You may take a +2 to skill checks with either the Endurance or Athletics skill, or you may add one of these skills to your class skill list when you create your character.

=== {{id name="Khem"/}}Khem ===

Your character is one of the hardy nomads of the far western land of Khem. The inhabitants of Khem are known as masters of the bow and horse, and are legendary for their endurance. You gain a +2 to Endurance skill checks or may add the Endurance skill to your class skills list when you create your character. You are fluent in the Khemish language instead of Common.</content></xwikidoc>
