<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xwikidoc>
<web>Player</web>
<name>ElfanHolds</name>
<language></language>
<defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
<translation>0</translation>
<parent>Player.Regions</parent>
<creator>XWiki.TodHarter</creator>
<author>XWiki.TodHarter</author>
<customClass></customClass>
<contentAuthor>XWiki.TodHarter</contentAuthor>
<creationDate>1335669455000</creationDate>
<date>1587692162000</date>
<contentUpdateDate>1587692162000</contentUpdateDate>
<version>8.1</version>
<title>The Elfan Holds</title>
<template></template>
<defaultTemplate></defaultTemplate>
<validationScript></validationScript>
<comment></comment>
<minorEdit>false</minorEdit>
<syntaxId>xwiki/2.1</syntaxId>
<hidden>false</hidden>
<content>The Elfan Holds is the generic name given to a large area of central Erithnoi which has been inhabited by various groups of elves and eldar since ancient times.

== Geography ==

The Elfan Holds are a large area in central Erithnoi lying between the Beldethian River on the west and the Uledraith River on the east. To the north they border on the Melthian Mountains and the Elath Teliar range. To the east are the [[Mid Realms&gt;&gt;Midrealms]], to the west is the Kingdom of Gilduin, and further north Kinergh.To the south is the [[Ta-Al-Erg&gt;&gt;Ta-Al-Erg]], the great inland sea to the south of Erithnoi.

The northernmost part of The Elfan Holds, north of High Hold, are mostly heavily forested and are home to Sildari Elves. The southern portions are more open and are inhabited by the Kernyi Elves. Scattered about the whole area are larger holds or towns. At the mouth of the Beldethian River is the great City of Seareach. On the eastern shore of [[Lake Tial&gt;&gt;LakeTial]], where the Holbrook River flows into the Beldethian from the west is located [[High Hold&gt;&gt;HighHold]].

== Politics ==

Elvish politics is considerably different from that of humans.There is no single recognizable authority analogous to the kings of human controlled lands. Elves rely heavily on reputation and those who are high in the esteem of their peers as leaders are usually styled Elven Lords by outsiders. Chief amongst these Lords is the Lord of High Hold, the most ancient and respected lineage amongst the Kernyi. The Sildari have their own Lords and the two groups usually only act together in times of crisis. Power struggles and wars amongst the elves are almost unknown. Those who disagree with others simply withdraw to their own holdings.

[[Sea Reach City&gt;&gt;SeaReach]] is somewhat of an anomaly in this regard. The city has a significant human population as well as a fair number of Eldarin inhabitants in addition to its Kernyi population. These elves are sometimes known as the Talari because of their habit of building ships and setting out on voyages across the oceans of Ergh. They are under the leadership of the Sea Princes. Most of the Sea Princes are Talari Elven Lords, but some are half elves or humans, and the crews of many of the ships combine members of all three races.

== The Eldar ==

The Eldar also frequent the Elfan Holds. Although they live mostly in the land of Fey, Eldarin individuals frequently travel by arcane magic to Erithnoi where they usually live for a time or do business in The Elfan Holds. High Hold in particular is frequented by eldar and much of the town has been shaped by or constructed with Eldarin magic. It is also rumored that the Eldar frequent the northern forests of the Sildari where they are most easily able to cross between the world of Fey and Erth. The Sildari are fairly reclusive however and the Eldar themselves rarely reveal their secrets either. So exactly what is contained in the forests of the north is mostly unknown to outsiders.</content></xwikidoc>
