<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xwikidoc>
<web>Player</web>
<name>GodOlorin</name>
<language></language>
<defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
<translation>0</translation>
<parent>Player.TheYoungerGods</parent>
<creator>XWiki.TodHarter</creator>
<author>XWiki.TodHarter</author>
<customClass></customClass>
<contentAuthor>XWiki.TodHarter</contentAuthor>
<creationDate>1335737433000</creationDate>
<date>1335737494000</date>
<contentUpdateDate>1335737494000</contentUpdateDate>
<version>1.1</version>
<title>Olorin</title>
<template></template>
<defaultTemplate></defaultTemplate>
<validationScript></validationScript>
<comment></comment>
<minorEdit>false</minorEdit>
<syntaxId>xwiki/2.1</syntaxId>
<hidden>false</hidden>
<content>== (night,sleep,magic,god,unaligned) ==

Olorin is the god of night, darkness, and the hidden forces of the mind. He is the dreaming god, the god of mystics and obscure knowledge. This also fits in with his role as the patron god of magic.

Olorin is widely worshiped by humans, rarely by other races. His followers are found all over Erithnoi. Their temples are usually constructed underground and may be located anywhere. Usually the sites are chosen for their mystic significance. For instance there is a temple in the town of Tisloch in the Kinergh known as Er-Aracak-Yul, the Temple of the Springing Rock. It is in the town and houses a large rock which is considered by many mages to have mystical powers. Other temples are located far from any inhabited locations.

Worship of Olorin revolves around certain mystical precepts which guide his followers lives. There are several forms of meditation and various exercises of mind and body which are supposed to provide benefits to health etc. Followers of Olorin tend to assign significance to everything they come upon and are sometimes considered overly credulous by others.

Temples are places where the faithful come to find guidance and revere the god. Regular ceremonies are held at night every 5 ^^th^^ day. Major ceremonies are held on the last day of each intercalary period. A ceremony consists of groups of worshipers chanting rhythmically and sometimes dancing. Each ceremony ends with meditation. Many of the details of these ceremonies are secret and are not revealed to outsiders.</content></xwikidoc>
