<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xwikidoc>
<web>Player</web>
<name>Imotnoi</name>
<language></language>
<defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
<translation>0</translation>
<parent>Player.TheYoungerGods</parent>
<creator>XWiki.TodHarter</creator>
<author>XWiki.TodHarter</author>
<customClass></customClass>
<contentAuthor>XWiki.TodHarter</contentAuthor>
<creationDate>1335737354000</creationDate>
<date>1335737422000</date>
<contentUpdateDate>1335737422000</contentUpdateDate>
<version>1.1</version>
<title>Imotnoi</title>
<template></template>
<defaultTemplate></defaultTemplate>
<validationScript></validationScript>
<comment></comment>
<minorEdit>false</minorEdit>
<syntaxId>xwiki/2.1</syntaxId>
<hidden>false</hidden>
<content>== (messengers,gates,lesser god,unaligned) ==

Imotni is the key master, opener of ways, keeper of the gates of time and space. He is also the patron god of all messengers, especially those who travel by magical means. All magical means of travel are sacred to Imotni, as are many normal gates and bridges.

Imotni is neither mail nor female, instead he/she/it is completely androgynous. Whereas the elven deities are prone to manifest as both male and female forms at different times Imotni never has a determinable sex.

Imotni is not a very extensively worshiped deity. Some magically inclined individuals pay homage to him, but he has few actual priests. Those priests which do exist usually busy themselves traveling to areas where places sacred to Imotni are located. They care for these shrines and instruct others in the precepts of the god. They teach that the multiverse is made up of many worlds and much of their teaching deals with lore about the inhabitants and contents of these other worlds. Priests of Imotni are the most likely individuals to have knowledge of the other planes of existence. Another major theme is watchfulness and guarding against possible ruptures in the fabric of the multiverse or incursions from other worlds. They will always seek to prevent experimentation with planar magic which is not done in a careful and controlled way. They are interested in such magics themselves, and always attempt to gain these "holy items" or knowledge of them.</content></xwikidoc>
