<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xwikidoc>
<web>Player</web>
<name>WebHome</name>
<language></language>
<defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
<translation>0</translation>
<parent></parent>
<creator>XWiki.Admin</creator>
<author>XWiki.TodHarter</author>
<customClass></customClass>
<contentAuthor>XWiki.TodHarter</contentAuthor>
<creationDate>1335064808000</creationDate>
<date>1584695119000</date>
<contentUpdateDate>1584695119000</contentUpdateDate>
<version>8.1</version>
<title>Player Information</title>
<template></template>
<defaultTemplate></defaultTemplate>
<validationScript></validationScript>
<comment></comment>
<minorEdit>false</minorEdit>
<syntaxId>xwiki/2.1</syntaxId>
<hidden>false</hidden>
<content>= Welcome to Erithnoi =

Erithnoi is the northwestern sub-continent of the vast land-mass of Ergh, the Earth. Erithnoi is named after the first Cardolan Emperor, Erithnoi the Great. The Cardolans arrived in Erithnoi 1004 years ago, refugees from a land far across the Untread Waters. For 600 years the Cardolans built an empire. Strong just Emperors first conquered easternmost Erithnoi and then gradually conquered most of the continent. 650 years later internal dissension and humanoid invasions destroyed the empire. Dark ages followed. In most areas humans eventually expelled the humanoid tribes. Now small kingdoms, humanoid dominated regions, and nascent empires control patchwork territories. Vast regions still exist where no humans normally travel. Expanding frontier areas encroach on areas that were barely explored in the days of the empire. Ancient monuments and artifacts give proof that long before the Empire there were other peoples, other nations, nations which possessed Lost knowledge...

Please explore!

== Topics ==

These topics provide general background information about Erithnoi which is common knowledge to its inhabitants.

* [[History&gt;&gt;doc:History]] - The history of Erithnoi.
* [[Religion&gt;&gt;doc:Religion]] - The gods of Erithnoi.
* [[Races&gt;&gt;doc:Races]] - The inhabitants of Erithnoi.
* [[Regions&gt;&gt;doc:Regions]] - The lay of the land. This includes knowledge of geography, politics, history, etc of all the different areas of Erithnoi which is common knowledge amongst its inhabitants. You can find maps here too!
* [[Calendar&gt;&gt;doc:Calendar]] - The seasons, sky, and related things. How time is kept in Erithnoi.
* [[Languages&gt;&gt;doc:Languages]] - The speech of the inhabitants of Erithnoi.
* [[Money&gt;&gt;doc:Money]] - Currency of Erithnoi, past and present.
* [[Character Backgrounds&gt;&gt;doc:CharacterBackgrounds]] - Detailed geographic backgrounds for Erithnoi PCs (using 4th Edition Background rules).

== Useful Stuff ==

[[Some generally useful links and handy references.&gt;&gt;doc:UsefulInfo]]

== Campaigns ==

Work areas and logs for campaigns

* [[Midrealms Campaign&gt;&gt;doc:MidrealmsCampaign]] - Deorai, Celery, Moose, and Penelope and their amusing adventures in the Midrealms.
* [[Eldoran Isles Campaign&gt;&gt;doc:EldoranIslesCampaign]] - The Magnusson's seek their fortunes on the high seas.
* [[Second Midrealms Campaign&gt;&gt;doc:SecondMidrealmsCampaign]] - Jeorai, Moore, Ore, Les, and more
* [[Third Midrealms Campaign&gt;&gt;doc:ThirdMidrealmsCampaign]] - Gillian</content></xwikidoc>
